# ABDULLAH WAFY

abdullah.wafy786@gmail.com 916-583-4512 Linkedin Github Portfolio

SKILLS React, Redux, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Node.js, Javascript, Express.js, SQL, Git, HTML5, CSS3

#### **PROJECTS**

**Custom Crafts** (React.js, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python3, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Alembic, SQL, GraphQL)

Live Site | Github A fullstack single-page e-commerce application where users can view custom-made spaceships, purchase them, and write reviews of their favorite ships.

- Implemented the Blender App to create 3-D models of customized spacecrafts for our e-commerce shop where you
  manipulated the spacecrafts in 3D and on 2D axes while also adding color to them which enhanced the UI and rendered a
  through-line design.
- Contributed to the Splash page, Shopping Cart, Order Summary and Profile pages in a group dynamic utilizing the git workflow
  and React.js to write the code for the Shopping Cart table, implement the logic of increasing and decreasing the quantity of
  items laying the groundwork for all frontend components.

Clack (Javascript, HTML5, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, Pug.js, SQL, Sequelize ORM and Socket.io)

Live Site | Github

A fullstack multiple-page live chat with emoji-switch where users can live-chat in real-time, add channels, and edit their profiles.

- Managed and led the team on the frontend UX and UI utilizing CSS and Pug.js to design the Splash and the live chat-room
  pages, where styling decisions were made emulating web leaders in CSS grid for aesthetic visual UI appeal, resulting in the
  carousel slide-show and modern parallax scrolling effect.
- Implemented WebSockets with Socket.IO to enable real-time chat functionality, creating a highly dynamic user experience.
- Ensured that live-chat has auto-scrolling capability with Javascript events--the built-in "scroll into view" Web API method and CSS overflow property.
- Enabled audio-sound when text messages are sent and broadcasting features by utilizing the html audio element tag and finding appropriate audio sounds for 'clicks' when sending messages.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Salam Elementary School, Teacher Sacramento, CA

2011-2013

- Taught & managed a classroom of nineteen 3rd grade students in multiple subjects: English (Reading, Handwriting, Composition, Spelling), Math, Science, Social Studies, PE and Art.
- Communicated with staff, faculty and parents via one-on-one meetings, conferences, e-mail.
- Maintained student grades via data entry in an online database via a teacher-parent app where grades and comments were
  entered and correspondence maintained.

## Al-Arqam College Prep, Instructor Sacramento, CA

2009-2011

- Designed & drafted the prestigious two-year International Baccalaureate Honors History curriculum for seniors.
- Instructed High School IB History Honors for the juniors & seniors, Middle School Honors English for 7th & 8th grades.
- Executed role of Home Room Teacher for my 7th grade students and Physical Education Instructor for sophomores.

### **EDUCATION**

## App Academy Online, CA

2020

1000-hour rigorous & immersive full-stack software development course with < 3% acceptance rate.</li>

### Career Break - Study Abroad Middle East

2013-2017

• 4 year immersive cultural and linguistic sabbatical.

#### UC Davis (University of California) Davis, CA

2007-2009

Bachelor of Arts in Classical Civilizations with emphasis on Ancient Greek & Classical Latin languages & literatures.

### Cosumnes River College (part of Los Rios Community Colleges) Sacramento, CA

2004-2007

• AA - Associate of Arts in English with Honors.